Hi, guys! This is Pearce with SparkFun Engineering, and today I'm going to show how to assemble
the Elastolite. It's a really cool EL panel. It's waterproof. It's super bendable
and works great in clothing. So, now we have all of our parts in front of us.
If you are doing anything different then what we are doing here today,
go on the tutorial on learn.sparkfun.com, and it'll explain a little more into using the T-connector,
uh using multiple straight connectors, things like that.
For this were just going to use the 3 by 5 Elastolite lamp; the 3 feet of iron on circuitry;
the two straight connectors with the two pieces of iron on tape;
the molex connector with the exposed wires; and of course the INV133.
The tools you will need are laid out in front of me. You'll need an iron.
The iron needs to be set to cotton. You'll need a hobby knife.
Wax paper, if your not going to directly iron this into a garment.
The first thing we're going to prep is the two inches of iron on tape.
We're going to fold over the piece of tape and then cut it in two,
giving us 2 one inch parts. This is going to go on the outside of the straight connectors
to make sure it can be ironed into the garment. So, now we are going to trim the molex leads.
There's 4 leads, but only 2 of them actually have any current flowing through them.
The two leads we are gong to want are the red and the tan lead.
The other two we are going to clip off. Next, we are going to trim the leads
on the three feet of iron-on circuitry. We are going to make 3 incisions
in the iron on part of the circuitry. Be sure not to nick the thread parts as that
can lead to a premature failure of the circuit. We're going to firmly pull the sheathing off
to expose the two threads. The one side that's gong to connect to the lamp were going
to want to trim about quarter of an inch. On the other side which connects
to the molex connector were gonna want three quarters of an inch to an inch.
So, now we're going to make the connector that connects between the molex connector
to the iron on circuitry. We're going to need the two straight connectors,
and the two pieces of iron-on tape. We're going to set down the first piece
of iron-on tape sticky side up. If you can't figure out what the sticky side is
hold it firmly between your two fingers and rub it back and forth.
The sticky side will stick to your finger where as the other side
will slide around. Then we are going to put down the straight connector on top of it.
You're going to want to put the straight connector down so the letters up are
facing you, so you can read the word up. This means that the part that's going to bond
with the other side of the straight connector is facing inward.
Once you have these two in place, you're going to want to put down the
exposed threads from the iron-on circuitry, and the two exposed wires
from the molex connector. Once you have those in a place they'll make a solid connection,
you're going to put the other straight connector on top.
Once that's in place, you're going to want to put a final piece of iron-on tape on
top of it. Now that you have that all together, we can iron it to bond the connection.
Hold it on anywhere from 10 to 20 seconds. Be sure to provide only minimum force;
you want gravity to be doing the work. You shouldn't be pushing down at all.
Now you need to make the connection between the iron-on circuitry and the lamp.
You're going to put the iron on circuitry and place it right over
0:023:53.50, 0:02:57.50
the two connection points coming off the Elastolite lamp.
It should be the two gray splotches that are off on the color border.
Once you put that down and the circuitry is in place, you're going to take the connection
points which came with the lamp, and put those on top of it,
making sure the circuitry is sandwiched between the two.
Once everything is in place there you just iron it on
just like the other one: put just a little bit of pressure on the points
and wait for the bond to happen. You're going to need to cover up the other
connection point on the lamp as those are live connection points.
If it folds over and they touch, it can short out the circuit.
You're gonna put the connector patches on top the open point, and you're going to put
minimal pressure on the iron and just let the bond occur.
Once that's all dry, you should be all set and you can plug in your inverter and see if it works.
[Outro Music]